<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Bao Nguyen</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Bao Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Charger - Junior Design Project</title>
      <link>/projects/juniordesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/juniordesign/</guid>
      <description>For our final junior design project, our team of 3 made a solar charger that take in power from a 170W solar panel to charge:
 Sealed Lead-Acid battery Li-ion battery USB-C device with USB PD compliant  The charger follow the charging curve of the battery using constant current, constant voltage, and floating phase. I was in charged of design, fabricate and testing the main charging PCB. I also wrote the Graphical User Interface using Tkinter on Python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eDNA Sampler</title>
      <link>/projects/ednasampler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/ednasampler/</guid>
      <description>The first project lead was Kawin Pechetratanapanit for the embedded software and myself for hardware (mechanical and electrical). I designed electrical hardware from the Logic to the Power module. Furthermore, I also design the first version of the sampler from tubing to filter design. The project was aimed to reduce labor costs and long sampling duration for a remote location.
Overview Organisms leave traces of DNA as they move through their environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenSampler</title>
      <link>/projects/watersampler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/watersampler/</guid>
      <description>OpenSampler is designed to be an Open Source fully-automated water sampler that allows a greater degree of customization and the ability to add external sensor of choice. I was in charge of the electronics and advising the overall mechanical design. The code was adopted from the eDNA with some customization.
More detail More about this project can be found on OpenSensing Lab Wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossover Amplifier</title>
      <link>/projects/crossoveramplifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/crossoveramplifier/</guid>
      <description>In Winter term 2019, I was taking the Fundamental Electrical course where my teammate and I got to design filters with amplifier for speakers. The goal in this lab was to design and build a functioning 3-range speaker system (high range, low range, and mid-range) using a high pass, low pass and band pass filter with an amplifier for each of the filters. It was to gain more understanding of how a filter works, how to apply a schematic to build a circuit on a breadboard or solder it onto a perfboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bio Reactor Control Board</title>
      <link>/projects/bioreactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/bioreactor/</guid>
      <description>The circuit that I made is to control two 12v peristaltic pumps with the information from a temperature sensor and a liquid pressure sensor. The brain of the project is an Arduino Nano which runs directly on a 12v power supply.
Feature
 Programable with Arduino NANO x2 speed control for peristaltic pump x1 waterproof DS18B20 temperature sensor x1 PendoTECH inline pressure sensor x2 interupt buttons  How did I start?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>