<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Bao Nguyen</title>
    <link>/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Bao Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an undergraduate electrical engineering student at Oregon State Unversity. I am interested in digital logic design and device physic and wanted to go on the IC design track at OSU. I am also pursuing a minor in Computer Science and Chemistry.
In the past year, I have been working at the OSU OpenSening Lab where I led a team in hardware design to make a DNA sampling machine from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junior Design</title>
      <link>/projects/juniordesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/juniordesign/</guid>
      <description>For our final funior design project, our team made a solar charger that take in power from a 170W solar panel to charge:
 Sealed Lead-Acid battery Li-ion battery USB-C device with USB PD compliant  The charger follow the charging curve of the battery using constant current, constant voltage, and floating phase. I was in charged of design, fabricate and testing the main charging PCB. I also wrote the Graphical User Interface using Tkinter on Python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossover Amplifier</title>
      <link>/projects/crossoveramplifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/crossoveramplifier/</guid>
      <description>In Winter term 2019, I was taking the Fundamental Electrical course where my teammate and I got to design filters with amplifier for speakers. The goal in this lab was to design and build a functioning 3-range speaker system (high range, low range, and mid-range) using a high pass, low pass and band pass filter with an amplifier for each of the filters. It was to gain more understanding of how a filter works, how to apply a schematic to build a circuit on a breadboard or solder it onto a perfboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bio Reactor Control Board</title>
      <link>/projects/bioreactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/bioreactor/</guid>
      <description>The circuit that I made is to control two 12v peristaltic pumps with the information from a temperature sensor and a liquid pressure sensor. The brain of the project is an Arduino Nano which runs directly on a 12v power supply.
Feature
 Programable with Arduino NANO x2 speed control for peristaltic pump x1 waterproof DS18B20 temperature sensor x1 PendoTECH inline pressure sensor x2 interupt buttons  How did I start?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>